betway.com 2019-05-08

# Betway - Privacy Policy and Security

This Privacy Policy sets out: 

  * General information
  * Contact us
  * Data we collect
  * How we use your data
  * Who we share your data with 
  * How we store your data
  * Your rights
  * Cookie Policy

**General information**

Betway is managed by Betway Limited (hereinafter referred to as Betway). Betway is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and ensuring your security when you use our Services. This Privacy Policy is to help you understand what we do with your data and how we protect and process it. 

**Contact us**

Betway Limited is a data controller based in Malta. Our registered address is: 9 Empire Stadium Street, Gzira, GZR 1300, Malta.

If you have any questions regarding your personal data please contact our Data Protection Officer at [DataProtectionOfficer@betway.com](mailto:DataProtectionOfficer@betway.com). For any other requests please contact our Customer Support team on [support@betway.com](mailto:support@betway.com). 

**Data we collect**

During the registration process and when you subsequently use your Betway account, you are requested to submit specific personal data including but not limited to: 

  * your first and last name, 
  * date of birth, 
  * credit card or other payment data, 
  * home or another physical address, 
  * e-mail address, 
  * phone/mobile number,
  * other contact data,
  * your unique user name and password combination for your account. 

Once you have created an account and have become a Betway customer, additional information is processed on an on-going basis.  Betway may also collect:

  * a record of all internet communications and details of your visits to our Websites;
  * technical information relating to how you use our products, such as the type of device you are using and the browser you are using to access our Websites;
  * payment information and details of transactions you carry out through the site, including your payment, withdrawals and wagers;
  * communications with us or our employees, for examples, calls, emails, and messages sent through the live chat service;
  * information regarding your location, including IP address and traffic information;
  * any additional information you submit through the website for example on forums, chat rooms, comment sections or in response to quizzes and questionnaires;
  * pages that you visited including what you have clicked on. Please see the Cookie Policy below for more information;.
  * Sometimes we may also request photo ID, proof of address, and source of funds;
  * Occasionally we may also access your public records (eg.: news articles, social media, forums, official records such as the electoral roll).

To protect both you and us, we use Services provided by third parties to help us decide whether to accept transactions from you by assessing your method of payment, and the devices you use to visit our Websites. These third-party services check whether the device or method of payment has been identified with fraudulent or abusive transactions in the past, such as reported instances of identity theft, promotion abuse or credit card fraud.

**How we use your personal data**

We use your personal data to try and provide you with the ultimate Betway experience whilst ensuring we meet regulatory requirements, legal obligations and business related requirements. We process your personal data for the purposes of:

  * Creating your account and providing you with gambling services;

We use your personal data such as your name, DOB and email address to help set up your account and, if necessary, to contact you (according to your preferences) via your registered contact information in connection with the management and operation of your account.

We also use your personal data such as your device type, location and browser preferences to manage your account. We want to ensure that you can see the best version of Betway on your device and are authorised to use Betway in your current location. We do this based on our legal obligations and legitimate interests to provide you services. 

  * Ensuring our Websites function correctly and identifying any technical issues;

As we want to give our customers the ultimate Betway experience, we may also use your personal data to help with internal research and development, internal testing of the products and to help diagnose system issues and make content and service improvements to the website. This processing is required for the legal obligations and legitimate interests of Betway.

  * Ensuring you gamble responsibly;

Betway is committed to ensuring that you gamble responsibly. So, to abide by legal obligations we will process your data to provide you with a safe environment to gamble, as well as to monitor you for potential at-risk behaviour.

  * Identifying and verifying customers;

This includes the identification and verification of individuals under anti-money laundering legislation, ensuring customers are over 18 and to comply with responsible gambling rules and initiatives. To verify your age and the details that you registered your account with, we may disclose such information to approved third parties with many safeguards in place. This is required to meet our legal obligations. 

  * Legal and regulatory obligations;

We are required to process and retain your personal data including but not limited to your name, account number, date of birth and location to prevent fraudulent activity, to detect and/or investigate crimes, and to ensure responsible gambling. Additionally, we may also process your personal data to meet our internal and external reporting requirements. This is required to meet our legal obligations. 

  * Marketing;

Dependent on your marketing preferences, we will use your personal data to send you information by the contact methods you authorise us to use about our brands, products, competitions, prizes and offers for the purpose of marketing Betway's Services to you.

You can choose not to receive marketing/promotional material at any time by managing your marketing preferences via My Account. We also provide you with the opportunity to opt out by reply in every marketing message we send. 

If you have opted out of receiving marketing communications from us, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure you no longer receive promotional material about Betway. We may however still send you transactional emails, relating to the maintenance of, and changes to, your account. 

The information we send you about bonuses, promotions and markets is based on our legitimate interest.

  * Prevention of crime;

Betway has various policies and procedures designed to detect and prevent criminal activity. This includes fraud detection and our Anti-Money Laundering programme.  We carry out this processing to comply with our legal obligations.

  * Processing your online financial and wagering transactions;

We need to use your personal data such as your account details, payment type(s), deposit method(s) and wager history to allow you to deposit and withdraw, and for our regulatory reporting. This is to comply with our Terms and Conditions and legal obligations.

  * Profiling and your preferences;

Betway will create new personal data about you by processing your data including but not limited to your betting and gameplay behaviour, interests, location and age to develop new features, functionality, products and services that are tailored to you. This will help us to ensure that: 

  * the technical help you may need is in line with the device that you use, and 
  * the promotions you receive are in line with your preferences, and 
  * the customer support you receive is in line with your jurisdiction. 

Additionally, Betway researches your preferences to develop new features, functionality, products and services. This is in our legitimate interests. Additionally, this profiling is in our legal interests, as profiling of your personal data is for reasons such as meeting our legal requirements with regards to anti-money laundering, age verification, prevention of fraud, sports integrity and responsible gambling. 

  * Risk management;

We review customer profile and betting data for the purposes of enforcing our terms and conditions managing our financial liabilities and risk on events and markets. For more information please see section 7 of the General Terms and Conditions. This is both to comply with our legitimate interest and legal obligations.

**Who we share your personal data with**

Certain trusted third party companies provide services essential to our ability to offer our gambling products to you, for example those that supply the software and games for our Websites, banking and payment services, identity verification, fraud prevention and risk management. We may be required to share some of your information with these companies, some of which may be based outside the European Economic Area (EEA), to be able to offer our Services to you. In these instances, we ensure that the third party has appropriate security and privacy arrangements in place, so that your data is protected.

Betway may also be required to disclose your information to government authorities, such as the police or our regulators, to comply with our legal obligations. Personal information may also be shared with regulators, agencies or relevant sports bodies where there are suspicions of involvement in match-fixing or breach of sports regulations. We will also disclose information as required to enforce our terms of use as stated in the [Terms and Conditions.](https://betway.com/en/policies/terms/)

In the event of the sale of our business, or other business event, which results in us having to transfer your personal data to a third party, you will be notified via email, or notice posted on our website, to explain the identity of the new data controller and your options regarding your personal data.

Our site may contain links to and from the Websites of third party organisations. Please note that these Websites may have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility whatsoever for these policies. Please check these policies carefully before you submit any personal data

**How we store your personal data**

Betway is incorporated in Malta and your data is stored within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) on our servers. But where we work with third parties, the data we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the EEA. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, customer services, the processing of your payment details and risk/fraud management.

We ensure there are appropriate contractual controls over any third party that helps us process your data, which ensuring that your rights are upheld and your data is secure.

We store your data for as long as you are an active customer with us. Once you are no longer our customer, we will hold your personal data on our systems for as long as is necessary to comply our legal obligations in your jurisdiction, such those imposed by tax, gambling and AML laws.

**Your Rights**

You are a data subject, your personal data belongs to you, so you have rights over your personal data. Some of these rights only apply in certain circumstances. 

If you want more information you can contact [support@betway.com](mailto:support@betway.com), or if you would like to exercise your rights, you can submit a request via the [online webform](https://uk.digitalrisk.saiglobal.com/SARPortal_104/). 

These are your fundamental rights:

**Your right to** | **What does that mean?**  
---|---  
Access | You have the right to know whether personal data   concerning you is being processed and can also request a copy of your data.  
Rectification | You have the right to easily amend incorrect personal   data about yourself.  
Erasure | You have the right to request ‘to be forgotten’. You   can ask us to delete you from our database.  
Restrict processing | You can tell us that you do not want your data used   for a particular purpose.  
Be informed | We need to let you know what we do with your personal   data in this privacy policy or when you ask us.  
Data portability | You can ask us to provide the personal data you   provided us in a machine-readable format.  
Object | You can object to us processing your personal data.  
  
Please note that these rights are not absolute and requests are subject to any applicable legal requirements, including gambling regulations and other legal and ethical reporting or document retention obligations. 

For any further queries related to your rights, you can submit an email to [DataProtectionOfficer@betway.com](mailto:DataProtectionOfficer@betway.com).

If you have any concerns about your rights, don’t forget that you always have the right to complain to a data protection regulator. Betway is regulated by the [Office of Information and the Data Protection Commissioner (IDPC)](https://idpc.org.mt/en/Pages/Home.aspx)

**Cookie Policy**

Cookies are text files containing a small amount of information that are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. They are generally used by most websites to improve your online experience and to ensure that content and functions are delivered and used more effectively.

Cookies perform various different functions. For example, some cookies are session cookies, which are downloaded to your device temporarily for the period that you browse a particular website; these cookies might allow you to navigate between pages more efficiently or enable websites to remember the preferences you select. Other cookies are persistent cookies, which can be used to help websites remember you as a returning visitor or ensure the online adverts you receive are more relevant to your specific needs and interests

The primary use of cookies on our Websites, either directly by ourselves or our chosen partner(s), is to: enable you to save time and facilitate future access to the site; identify how people navigate through our website to improve our Service, content and the effectiveness of our communications; collect and share device data to detect and prevent devices associated with fraud and money laundering; identify account and device irregularities and detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and abuse of our customer accounts and our Services.

You agree that Betway may, from time to time, place cookies on your device to save information (such as user name, password, other personal details, e-mail address, technical device information such as the model and its IP address) to make full use of the functionality and Services on our website and to allow your browser to identify you as a user. This enables you to not have to re-enter this information each time you visit the Betway site. These cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer, and are uniquely assigned to you. These cookies can only be read by the web server(s) that placed the cookies on your device.

At any time you can amend your browser settings to block some or all cookies from Betway. However, if you block cookies from Betway some or all the website's functions may not perform as intended. For example, you may not actually be able to place any bets.

Some examples of the types of cookies used by Betway include, but are not limited to:

Cookie type | Purpose  
---|---  
Security and authentication | These cookies are essential in providing our services and preform functions such as helping to authenticate your details, keep your information secure, ensuring you are able to login into your account, and keeping you logged in as you move from one part of our website to the next. An example of this type of cookie is _RequestVerificationToken, which ensures you are logging in to the correct account.  
Preferences, features and services | These cookies help to improve your experience on our website. For example, they help to remember preferences you have selected, help to show you the correct version of the website for your location, offer you services such as Live Chat and remember whether you accepted the terms and conditions. An example of this type of cookies is LPVID, which allow us to offer Live Chat functionality from different webpages on our website.  
Performance and analytics | These cookies help us see how players are using our website, to identify any performance issues, and to improve how our products work. Examples of these types of cookies are _ga and _gid. These Google Analytics cookies help us track what pages players are visiting and which features of the website are being used.  
  
Further information about cookies can be found at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Changes to this policy**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, so please re-visit this page frequently. We will provide notice of substantial changes of this Privacy Policy and will send you a notice or an e-mail regarding such changes. Otherwise, all other changes to this Privacy Policy are effective as of the stated “Last updated” date, and your continued use of the Services after the Last Revised date will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes.

**_Last updated:_** _29/01/2019, 09:00 GMT_
